MONIKA MAGDY MORCOS

PHARMACIST - MEDICAL TRANSLATOR

Egypt

monikamagdymorcos@gmail.com

01211216233

PROFILE INFO

I am a friendly and conscientious pharmacist with experience optimizing medication therapy under the Egyptian Ministry of Health. Highly accurate and detail-oriented, I provide quality translations between English and Arabic, specializing in clinical trials, medical reports, and analyses. I ensure the integrity and nuances of original texts while meeting strict deadlines.

EDUCATION

2014-2019

ALEXANDRIA UNIVERSITY

- Bachelor of pharmacy
- Grade: very good

2022-2023

ARAB ACADEMY FOR **SCIENCE, TECHNOLOGY &** MARITIME TRANSPORT

- · Quality health care diploma
- GPA: Very Good

SKILLS

- · Microsoft ward
- Microsoft power point
- Microsoft publisher
- · Pharmafly programme
- CAT tools for translation

LANGUAGES

- Arabic (Native)
- English (Fluent)
- Italian (Basics)
- French (Basics)

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Coordinator of the Drug Committee of Egyptian Ministry of Health's Al-Atarin Clinic. 2024 - PRESENT
 - · Maintaining and updating the clinic's drug formulary, which is a list of approved medications.
 - Scheduling and organizing meetings.
 - Providing education and training to clinic staff on appropriate medication use.
 - Disseminating information on new drug therapies and medication safety updates.
 - Collaborating with healthcare professionals.
 - Monitoring and reporting adverse drug reactions.
 - Implementing strategies to prevent medication errors.
- Pharmacist at the Egyptian Ministry of Health's Al-Atarin Clinic.

2023 - PRESENT

- · Work with coronavirus vaccination campaigns at Egyptian Ministry of Health's Al-Atarin Clinic. 2022-2023
- Pharmacist and head of cosmetics department at Dr. Abu Elala pharmacy.

2021-PRESENT

- Dispensed medications, provided patient counseling, and managed drug interactions.
- Reviewed and interpreted prescriptions, ensuring accuracy and safety.
- Directing patients toward over-the-counter medications to treat their ailment.
- behave in a professional manner.
- · creating promotions and videos for the cosmateic department in the pharmacy and guide the patient to the suitable product based on their skin type, hair, etc.
- Pharmacist at Dr. Mervat saad pharmacy.

2020-2021

· Pharmacy manager at Dr. Eci pharmacy.

2019-2020

Alongside working at the pharmacy as a pharmacist. I place orders for the medications that have been sold from the pharmacy to the pharmaceutical companies, handle the billing with the companies at the end of the month, and deliver the daily earnings to the pharmacy owner.

· Private science tutor.

2020-2021

PROJECTS

Translation projects from English to Arabic at Motrjim Academy:

- · Translation of two blood analyses containing of different tests:
 - · Inflammatory Markers.
 - · liver function tests.
 - kidney function tests.
 - · Cardiac Markers.
 - · complete blood picture.

· Translation of Articles about:

- · Acute respiratory distress syndrome.
- · Mechanism of drug resistance in cancer.
- Epigenetic mechanism in cancer progression and therapy resistance.
- Advancements in biomedical devices: key components and functions.
- Translation of the Flagyl drug brochure.
- Translation of the brochure on flu caused by H1N1.
- · Translation of MRI, MRA, MRV scan of the brain.
- Translation of multi slice non contrast CT scan of the orbits, in the axial and coronal planes.
- Translation of DUPLEX & COLOR ULTRASOUND of the deep venous system of both lower limbs.

Projects for dental students:

- Causes of teeth coloration poster by Microsoft word.
- Principle of smile design poster by Microsoft word.
- Anti-hypertensive drugs poster by Microsoft ward.
- NSAIDS brochure by Microsoft publisher.
- CAD/CAM technology in dentistry brochure by Microsoft publisher.
- · Comparison between amaglam and composite restoration brochure by Microsoft publisher.
- Gap analysis with action plan of GAHAR standards project by Microsoft power point.

CERTIFICATES

- · First aid course at faculty of medicine.
- Role of Primary Health Care In context of Covid-19 Pandemic course from World Health Organization.
- · Requirements of pharmacy practice program at Egyptian drug authority.
- Medical translation online course at Motrjim Academy.
- · Covid-19 treatment, vaccine and post-covid syndrome online course by EVA pharmacist academy.
- Harvard university:
 - · coping with the stress of Coronavirus.
 - Pregnancy and breast feeding during COVID-19.
 - COVID-19 Vaccine development and novel therapeutics.
 - The impact of COVID-19 on telehealth.
 - Covid-19 And Loss of smell.

Coursera:

- Anti-microbial resistance course at technical university of Denmark.
- Fundamentals of immunology at Rice university.
- Tricky American English Pronunciation at university of California, Irvine.
- · Anatomy specialization at university of Michigan.
- · Creative writing specialization at Wesleyan university.
- Mindfulness in integrative healthcare course at university of Minnesota.

• Future learn online courses:

- Plagues, Pestilence and Pandemics at Griffith university.
- COVID-19 tackling the novel Coronaviruse by UK public health rapid support team.